A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 3, Accession 3 FA1185
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Programs, Projects, and Proposals, 1980-2014; 8
  - FA1185:011 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 57), 1992 May 10-22; Still Images: 5 color 3x5 prints. (Box 34, Folder 170)
    Images of delegates at Williamsburg and in New York. Some images are from an earlier, 1990, delegation.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 60-63), 1993 May -September (Box 19, Folder 171)
    SOP 60, 1993 May 16-29, Journalism; SOP 61, 1993 June 17-30, International Relations; SOP 62, 1993 July 22 - August 4, English Language and Literature; SOP 63, 1993 August 19 - September 1, Economics. SOP 62 file includes photo of Guangda Huang and Debra Kam.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 65-67), 1994 May-July (Box 20, Folder 172)
    SOP 65, 1994 May 12-25, Journalism; SOP 66, 1994 June 4-16, English Language and Literature; SOP 67, 1994 July 7-20, International Relations, Economics, and Law.
  - FA1185:012 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 66), 1994 June 4-16; Still Images: 9 color 3x5 - 4x6 prints (Box 34, Folder 172)
    English Language and Literature delegation visit to League of Women Voters and New York Urban League, and group photo.
  - FA1185:013 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 67), 1994 July; Still Images: 2 color 3x5 prints (Box 34, Folder 172)
    Group photo of delegation and of a delegate with Maria Casa in front of the White House. Enclosed in Yang, Li to Maria Casa, October 6, 1995. (Images may be for a later delegation? No Yang Li found on namelist.)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 68-70), 1995 June-August (Box 20, Folder 173)
    SOP 68, 1995 June 11-24, Economics, Law, and Management; SOP 69, 1995 July 9-22, English Language and Literature; SOP 70, 1995 August 13-26, International Relations, American Studies.
  - FA1185:014 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 68), 1995 June 11-24; Still Images: 2 color 3x5 prints (Box 34, Folder 173)
    2 images of Maria Casa and Yan Lu, enclosed in Lu to Maria Casa, August 26, 1995.
  - FA1185:015 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 70), 1995 August 13-26; Still Images: 14 color 4x6 images. (Box 34, Folder 173)
    Group photo of delegation, sent by Ren Ying, September 16, 1995; 3 photos (similar group photo, plus two images of delegates with Maria Casa), enclosed in letter from Jin Yamin, received September 28, 1995; 3 photos of delegates' trip, enclosed in Ren Ying to Maria Casa, September 16. 1995; 2 images of Maria Casa and delegate, enclosed in Peimin Lu to Maria Casa, October 28, 1995; 5 images of delegates' trip, enclosed in Ren Gongping to Maria Casa, August 30, 1995.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 71): General, 1996 April 28-May 11 (Box 20, Folder 174)
    International Relations, Economics, and Law. Includes program planning.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 71): Participants, 1996 April 28-May 11 (Box 20, Folder 175)
    International Relations, Economics, and Law. Includes applications and invitation letters.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 71): Evaluation Forms, 1996 April 28-May 11 (Box 20, Folder 176)
    International Relations, Economics, and Law
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 71): Thank Yous, 1996 April 28-May 11 (Box 20, Folder 177)
  - FA1185:016 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 71): Thank Yous, 1996 April 28-May 11; Still Images: 3 color prints (3x5 - 4x6) (Box 34, Folder 177)
    Delegates with Jason Recate and group photo at Hyde Park. Enclosed in letters from Xie Zhaoguo and from Ding Bangquan.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 72): General, 1996 June 16-29 (Box 20, Folder 178)
    Women's Studies
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 72): Participants, 1996 June 16-29 (Box 20, Folder 179)
    Women's Studies. Includes applications and invitation letters.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 72): Programming, 1996 June 16-29 (Box 20, Folder 180)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 72): Evaluation Forms, 1996 June 16-29 (Box 21, Folder 181)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 72): Thank Yous and Follow-Up, 1996 June 16-29 (Box 21, Folder 182)
  - FA1185:017 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 72): Thank Yous and Follow-Up, 1996 June 16-29; Still Images: 10 color prints (3x5 - 4x6) (Box 34, Folder 182)
    Images and group photos of SOP 72 delegates, enclosed in cards and notes from delegates to Nina Chan.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 73): General, 1996 July 28-August 10 (Box 21, Folder 183)
    Education, English Language and Literature, and American Studies. Includes Report and Thank Yous.
  - FA1185:018 - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 73): General, 1996 July 28-August 10; Still Images: 2 color 4x6 prints. (Box 34, Folder 183)
    Two images of delegates in Washington, DC, and Philadelphia. Enclosed in Wanling Zhang to Nina Chan, August 19, 1996.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 73): Participants, 1996 July 28-August 10 (Box 21, Folder 184)
    Education, English Language and Literature, and American Studies. Includes applications and invitation letters.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 73): Programming, 1996 July 28-August 10 (Box 21, Folder 185)
    Education, English Language and Literature, and American Studies.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 73): Evaluation Forms, 1996 July 28-August 10 (Box 21, Folder 186)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 75): General, 1997 May 4-17 (Box 21, Folder 187)
    Poverty Alleviation
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 75): Participants, 1997 May 4-17 (Box 21, Folder 188)
    Poverty Alleviation. Includes applications.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 75): Background Materials, 1997 May 4-17 (Box 21, Folder 189)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 75): Programming and Planning, 1997 May 4-17 (Box 21, Folder 190)
    Poverty Alleviation. Includes invoices.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 75): Evaluations, 1997 May 4-17 (Box 22, Folder 191)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 78): General, 1998 July 19-August 1 (Box 22, Folder 197)
    American Studies. Itinerary, namelists, and thank yous. Also includes Report for both 1998 programs (Teachers Orientation No. 77 and SOP No. 78).
  - Scholar Orientation Program ( No. 78): Applications, 1998 July 19-August 1 (Box 22, Folder 198)
    American Studies.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 78): Participants, 1998 July 19-August 1 (Box 22, Folder 199)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 78): Participants, 1998 July 19-August 1 (Box 22, Folder 199 A)
    Restricted - Confidential material.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 78): Programming and Planning, 1998 July 19-August 1 (Box 23, Folder 200)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 78): Evaluations, 1998 July 19-August 1 (Box 23, Folder 201)
  - Consular Orientation Program (SOP No. 79): General, 1999 January 24-February 6 (Box 23, Folder 202)
    American Studies. Itinerary, namelists, evaluations and thank yous.
  - Consular Orientation Program (SOP No. 79): Participants, 1999 January 24-February 6 (Box 23, Folder 203)
    American Studies
  - Consular Orientation Program (SOP No. 79): Programming and Planning, 1999 January 24-February 6 (Box 23, Folder 204)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 81): General, 1999 July 25 - August 7 (Box 24, Folder 210)
    American Studies. Includes Host Families.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 81): General, 1999 July 25-August 7; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch. (Box 24, Folder 210)
    Floppy disk labeled "SOP 81" was originally filed with file of SOP 81 "final" document versions.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 81): Applications, 1999 July 25-August 7 (Box 24, Folder 211)
    American Studies. Includes invitation letters.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 81): Programming and Visit Planning, 1999 July 25-August 7 (Box 24, Folder 212)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 81): Evaluations and Follow-Up, 1999 July 25-August 7 (Box 24, Folder 213)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 82): General, 2000 June 4-17 (Box 24, Folder 214)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 82): General (Disk 1), 2000 June 4-17; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 24, Folder 214)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 82): General (Disk 2), 2000 June 4-17; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 24, Folder 214)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 82): Applications, 2000 June 4-17 (Box 24, Folder 215)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 82): Participants, 2000 June 4-17 (Box 24, Folder 216)
    Includes decision letters (acceptances and declinations), agreement forms, and correspondence.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 82): Programming and Visit Planning, 2000 June 4-17 (Box 24, Folder 217)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 82): Evaluation Forms, 2000 June 4-17 (Box 25, Folder 218)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 84): General, 2001 June 3-16 (Box 25, Folder 224)
    Namelists, Itinerary, Acceptances, Correspondence, and Background Material.
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 84): Applications, 2001 June 3-16 (Box 25, Folder 225)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 84): Host Families, 2001 June 3-16 (Box 25, Folder 226)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 84): Programming and Visit Planning, 2001 June 3-16 (Box 26, Folder 227)
  - Scholar Orientation Program (No. 84): Evaluations and Follow-up, 2001 June 3-16 (Box 26, Folder 228)
  - Survey of Programs on United States-China Relations and Security Issues: Report, 2003 January 8 (Box 31, Folder 282)
    On behalf of the Ford Foundation, the National Committee surveyed American organizations concerning their programs relating to U. S. - China relations and security issues. This report was submitted to the Ford Foundation for its internal use. Two copies of report in file.
  - Survey of Programs on United States-China Relations and Security Issues: Report and Appendices, 2006 January 18, 2007 March (Box 32, Folder 283)
    Report dated 2006, marked "Second Ford Report," was an internal report to the Ford Foundation, updated from 2003 report. The report was subsequently published in March 2007 in the NCUSCR's China Policy Series, no. 23.
  - Survey of Programs on United States-China Relations and Security Issues: Correspondence, 2002-2008 (Box 32, Folder 284)
    Includes 2005 survey response for Insitute for Foreign Policy Analysis.
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: General (A-Z), 2002 (Box 32, Folder 285)
    Survey of Programs on International Relations and Security Issues involving the United States, China, and the Asia-Pacific Region - Questionnaire. Responses for Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies; John M. Olin Institute for Strategic Studies; Duke University, Center for International Studies; Stanford University, Center for International Security and Cooperation; University of Colorado, Boulder, Sino-American Security Dialogue; U. S. Naval War College; U. S. Military Academy, West Point; Henry L Stimson Center; Heritage Foundation.
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Atlantic Council, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 286)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Brookings Institution, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 287)
    Center for Northeast Asian Policy Studies (CNAPS).
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 288)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Center for Intelligence Research and Analysis (CIRA), 2005 (Box 32, Folder 289)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 290)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Pacific Forum CSIS, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 291)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: CNA Corporation, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 292)
    Center for Naval Analyses
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Committee on International Security and Arms Control (National Academy of Sciences), 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 293)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Council on Foreign Relations, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 294)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Fairbank Center for East Asian Research, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 295)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Georgetown University, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 296)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: George Washington University, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 297)
    Elliott School of International Affairs, Program for International Studies in Asia (PISA) and China Policy Program (Sigur Center for Asian Studies).
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Bonnie Glaser, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 298)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Harvard University, Kennedy School of Government, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 299)
    Asia Programs
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Kettering Foundation, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 300)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Mansfield Foundation, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 301)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: National Bureau of Asian research, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 302)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: National Committee on American Foreign Policy, 2002, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 303)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: National Defense University, 2002, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 304)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Nautilus Institute, Center for Pacific Rim, University of San Francisco, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 305)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Nixon Center, 2002, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 306)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Rand Corporation - Stanley Foundation, 2002, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 307)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Union of Concerned Scientists, 2002, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 308)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: University of California San Diego, Institute on Global Conflict and Cooperation (IGCC), 2002, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 309)
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: University of Denver - University of Georgia, 2002, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 310)
    Denver: Center for China - U. S. Cooperation; Georgia: Center for International Trade and Security
  - Ford Foundation Survey Responses: Woodrow Wilson International Center (Box 33, Folder 311)
  - Survey on Chinese Programs on International Relations and Asian Security Issues (for the MacArthur Foundation), 2006 Fall (Box 33, Folder 312)
  - 1990s Programs (General) (Box 33, Folder 316)
    Covering folder for 22 floppy disks (listed separately). Disks contain back-up files concerning various unspecified National Committee programs, exchanges, or events in the 1990s. May include administrative correspondence, notes, itineraries, reports. Box of disks labeled: "1990s Programs. Letters, notes, etc." Note inserted in box: "Peggy's Discs. Need to be looked over and cleaned up."
  - Back-up. Cov. file environ; files 5.0.environ, 1992 February [26]; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch (Box 33, Folder 316)
    Note on disk: Caution - nearly full.
  - Back-up: Ford, Environ, Gergen, Fund, [G]ACA, DML (David M. Lampton), HK, 1991 April; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch (Box 33, Folder 316)
    Notation on label: 6VCDE ?
  - ANPRT, Op Ed, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Broch. Sov 5.0; HPHRSEII.PRS; PTR.exe; Ford.cov, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - NCUSCR - Appeal Calendar, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Back-up. Win and Tran, USIA, USOD, Undated (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Ma [illegible], MA [illegible] 90, HO, Itin., Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Backup. Interp, Lunch, Calendar, Forms, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Backup. HK, Ford, Ford, EST., Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - China.dtf (BAckup, QU file, Chinese Contacts. 1 of 3, A-H., 1990 October 1; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - China2.dtf. Backup LIst (QA), 2 of 3, I-S, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - China3.dtf. Backup, 3 of 3 [illegible], T-Z; China4.dtf., 1990 November 1; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Miscellaneous Advis.sop, GRMP.iti, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Changes, NCUSCR newsletter, add, SCcon.lst.mrg, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
    Note on envelope: prog.tea
  - Final exams 215; USIA piece 637; Letters to National Committee; Resignation - Duan Lianchang, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
    Also marked on disk: Doak, Margot.
  - Letters - Wendy Locks TQs, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
    Note on envelope: Formatted (SOP).
  - China Report (Rice) (Word Perfect), Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Wendy Locks, filename: NPCLAC, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
    Note on envelope: Includes Canton.itn
  - SPC /and.F1, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - Elementary and Secondary Ed., Soviet, ACIL (.est, .sov), Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
  - HK, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
    "CATO" also written on label.
  - Japan Report - Immerman, Undated; Floppy disk: 5 1/4 inch. (Box 33, Folder 316)
- Ping Pong Diplomacy, 1997; 9
  - Ping Pong Diplomacy: Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Commemoration Table Tennis Balls, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 315)
    File is a placemarker only, for separated table tennis balls.
  - FA1185:031 - Ping Pong Diplomacy: Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Commemoration Table Tennis Balls, 1997; Realia: Two boxes of Ping Pong balls (Box FA1185:031, Folder 315)
    Two boxes of "Double Happiness" table tennis balls (3 balls in each).